<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tinted Tech</title>
    <description>Learn how to build awesome stuff with practical tutorials</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/imjustablacknerd/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/imjustablacknerd/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 02:05:03 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 02:05:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My path through web development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there! I’m excited to share my journey of diving into the fascinating world of web development, with JavaScript as my trusty sidekick. If you’re itching to embark on your own tech adventure, buckle up because I’ve got some insights to share!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;becoming-reactive&quot;&gt;Becoming Reactive&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got into the world of web development out of both curiosity and a determination to understand how websites are made. To start, I dived into the basics of web development. I went through lessons on HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, trying to absorb everything that makes up the web in simple terms. With Angular taking the stage as the main go-to framework, it was necessary to familiarize oneself with Node.js as well. At the time, I was only beginning to get a grip on things. I discovered that there was an entirely different world of interrelated technologies lying out there, waiting to be explored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continued learning more about web development I realized my love for JavaScirpt as my ally for everything code related. Starting from the fundamental concepts of variables, data types, loops, and functions, I laid a sturdy groundwork upon which I could construct more complex functionalities. I explored the modern features and capabilities of ES6, embracing advancements like arrow functions, classes, and template literals to enhance my coding prowess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got a solid understanding of JavaScript fundamentals, I set my sights on the vast array of frameworks that define contemporary web development. Mastery of JavaScript is paramount for navigating the diverse landscape of frameworks, particularly Angular, which reigned as the primary framework at the time. This powerful framework empowered developers to build dynamic and responsive web applications with remarkable efficiency. To excel in Angular development, I would have had to master concepts such as DOM manipulation, asynchronous programming, and state management. However before I felt ready to take Angular head on, Angular 2 was announced and was using Microsoft Typescript. At the time, I found the prospect of delving into further learning to be overwhelming, so I focused on honing my existing skills as a JavaScript Developer instead. However, this perception soon shifted when I realized that what I had initially deemed overwhelming was actually burnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking a much-needed break and allowing myself some time to recharge, I immersed back into my journey of learning web development. During this time, I stumbled upon React.js, a JavaScript library for building user interfaces. React.js seemed like the missing piece to my puzzle. Its component-based architecture and virtual DOM concept fascinated me, offering a more efficient way to build dynamic and interactive web applications. As I explored deeper into React.js, I found myself captivated by its simplicity and power in managing complex UIs. With each line of code I wrote, I could feel my understanding of web development growing stronger. React.js opened up new possibilities and challenged me to think differently about how I approach building web applications. It was a turning point in my journey, propelling me forward with newfound enthusiasm and determination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;React.js opened up a world of possibilities, allowing me to streamline development workflows and create dynamic web applications and broaden my horizons by exploring into other domains, such as desktop application development with Electron and mobile application development with React Native. Learning how to harness the capabilities of these platforms expanded my skill set and enabled me to create cross-platform applications that seamlessly integrate with various devices and operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, venturing into the realm of JavaScript frameworks like React.js marked a pivotal moment in my journey as a developer. It not only broadened my skill set but also ignited a passion for exploring new technologies and pushing the boundaries of what’s possible in web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;embracing-lifelong-learning&quot;&gt;Embracing Lifelong Learning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I look back on my journey, one thing stands out: learning is an ongoing adventure. Every line of code I write and every project I finish brings new challenges and chances to grow, both personally and professionally. This constant journey of exploration and improvement is what makes web development so exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re just starting out or deep into web development, it’s important to keep learning. With determination, persistence, and a curious mind, anyone can navigate the ever-changing world of technology. So, I encourage you to take that first step, dive into web development, and embrace the journey ahead. Because remember, it’s not just about reaching your goals, but the experiences you gain along the way, moments of discovery, growth, and innovation at every corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;resources-to-get-started&quot;&gt;Resources to Get Started:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online Courses I Used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn/2022/responsive-web-design/&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp’s Responsive Web Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn/javascript-algorithms-and-data-structures-v8/&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp’s JavaScript Algorithms &amp;amp; Data Structures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://githowto.com/&quot;&gt;Git How To&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BI1o2H9z9fo&quot;&gt;Traversy Media JavaScript Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fBNz5xF-Kx4&quot;&gt;Traversy Media Node Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w7ejDZ8SWv8&quot;&gt;Traversy Media React Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documentation and Tutorials:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/&quot;&gt;W3 Schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn&quot;&gt;Mozilla Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://javascript.info/&quot;&gt;Javascript Info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://react.dev/learn&quot;&gt;React JS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/docs/latest/api/&quot;&gt;Node Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://expressjs.com/&quot;&gt;Expressjs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community Forums:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.freecodecamp.org/&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/&quot;&gt;Dev.to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YouTube Channels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@TraversyMedia&quot;&gt;Traversy Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@WebDevSimplified&quot;&gt;Web Dev Simplified&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@funfunfunction&quot;&gt;Fun Fun Function&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these resources at your disposal, you’ll have everything you need to embark on your journey into the exciting world of web development. Remember, the key is to stay curious, keep learning, and never hesitate to explore new technologies and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/imjustablacknerd/my-path-though-web-development/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/imjustablacknerd/my-path-though-web-development/</guid>
        
        
        <category>web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my digital haven, where I invite you to join me on an exciting expedition through the vast landscape of technology. I’m thrilled to introduce myself and share the vision behind this blog, where I’ll be documenting my journey in the ever-evolving world of tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-am-i&quot;&gt;Who Am I?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go by Jay, a passionate individual with an insatiable curiosity for all things tech. Whether it’s the latest advancements in artificial intelligence, the intricacies of coding languages, or the innovative gadgets reshaping our daily lives, I’m here to immerse myself in the realm of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-this-blog&quot;&gt;Why This Blog?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embarking on this journey wasn’t just a personal choice; it’s a testament to the belief that knowledge becomes more valuable when shared. In this space, I aim to create a community where we can exchange ideas, insights, and experiences. Expect a blend of personal anecdotes, technical discoveries, and the occasional triumphs and challenges that come with navigating the tech landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-to-expect&quot;&gt;What to Expect?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is more than just a chronicle of my experiences—it’s a living, breathing entity that evolves with each new discovery. From tutorials and tech reviews to reflections on industry trends and personal breakthroughs, I’m committed to delivering content that inspires, educates, and fosters a sense of camaraderie among fellow tech enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to the journey ahead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jay&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/imjustablacknerd/helloworld/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/imjustablacknerd/helloworld/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Intro</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
